Guide to the Robert S. Einzig Papers SC1409
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Robert S. Einzig Papers
1948-2007
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Einzig, Robert S.
SC1409
1.5 Linear Feet
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift from Barbara Einzig, 2018.
Scope and Contents
The Robert S. Einzig papers include correspondence; reports and publications from the Transamerica Corporation; publications and reports regarding corporate finance and international currency concerns; material from Einzig's tenure at the U.C. Berkeley School of Business; Einzig's personal academic file; and material from the Bohemian Club.
Biographical / Historical
Robert S. Einzig earned an AB from Wayne State, and a PhD in Economics from the University of Michigan. He worked at the Transamerica Corporation and served as an adjunct professor of finance at the Haas School of Business at U.C. Berkeley.
Corporations -- Finance; Banks and banking; Business education -- United States.; Einzig, Robert S.; Transamerica Corporation; Bohemian Club (San Francisco, Calif.); Walter A. Haas School of Business (University of California, Berkeley)
- Correspondence
  - J.S.G. Wilson to Robert Einzig, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig James Meade - correspondence back and forth discussing single banking system, 1957 (Box 1)
  - James Meade to Robert Einzig, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Marget to Robert Einzig, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to Mr. Mangels, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Paul Einzig to Robert Einzig, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Henry A. Kissinger to Robert Einzig, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Andre Wormser to Robert Einzig (French), 1981 (Box 1)
  - M. le Professeur Gerard Bramouille to Robert Einzig (French), 1986 (Box 1)
  - Jean-Claude Gallienne to Robert Einzig, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to Blair Pascoe, R. Lindberg, D. Thomas and C. Carroux - Transamerican Memo, 1989 (Box 1)
  - John Myers to Robert Einzig, 1989 (Box 1)
  - John Myers to Robert Einzig, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Jim Harvey to Robert Einzig, Frank Herringer, Gary Depolo, Blair Pascoe and Kent Colwell, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to Blair Pascoe et al., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to John Van Praag, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to Dr. Helmut Schlesinger, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to John Van Praag, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Andre Wormser to Robert Einzig, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to Andre Wormser, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Neville Burston to Robert Einzig, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to Mr. Beuer, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to Peter Bernstein, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Peter Bernstein to Robert Einzig (Box 1)
  - Marcel Wormser to Robert Einzig, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Dick Breuer Robert Einzig - regarding the 50th anniversary of the fraternity Mu Beta Chi at Wayne State University, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Andre Wormser to Robert Einzig, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Marcel Wormser to Robert Einzig, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Marcel Wormser to Robert Einzig, 1997 Apr 15 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to Joseph Bisignano (Box 1)
  - Joseph Bisignano to Robert Einzig, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to John Van Praag, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to Bohemian Club, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to Robyn Frey, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to Marlene Burston, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Marlene Burston, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Andre Wormser to Robert Einzig, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Andre Wormser, 2001 Sep 13 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to Joseph Bisignano, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to Peter Foster, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to Andre Wormser, 2002 Apr 17 (Box 1)
  - Andre Wormser, 2002 Apr 4 (Box 1)
  - Andre Wormser to Robert Einzig, 2002 Apr 4 (Box 1)
  - Marcel Wormser to Robert Einzig, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Kent Colwell to Robert Einzig, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Kent Colwell to Robert Einzig (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to Joseph Bisignano, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to Joseph Bisignano, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Robert Einzig to Marcel Wormser, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper France-Amerique 4-10 Juillet 1974 (Box 1)
  - Photographs of Bob Frey and RE, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Photographs from Dresdner Bank press conference in Frankfurt, 1980 (Box 1)
- Banque d'Escompte
  - 50th Anniversary report, 1987 (Box 1)
- Transamerica Publications
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Photograph for Annual Report (Box 1)
  - Time Magazine, 1986 (Box 1)
- Transamerica and other Reports
  - International Monetary Problems and Trust Investment, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Risk and the Return of Capital (Box 1)
  - Transamerica TIMES, 1966 (Box 1)
  - "Prospects for Devaluation of the British Pound", 1966 Jul 11 (Box 1)
  - Transamerica Corporation Annual Report, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Transamerica Magazine, No. 1, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Compagnie Europeenne de Banque (Box 1)
  - Transamerica Corporation Annual Report, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Transamerica Corporation Annual Report, 1973 (Box 1)
  - White House Visit, 1974 (Box 1)
  - The Outlook on Inflation (heavily annotated), 1975 (Box 1)
  - "Financial Markets" delivered to a panel on "The Shape of the Future", 1976 (Box 1)
  - Final Report of the Inflation Policy Committee (includes action papers), 1976 (Box 1)
  - "Foreign Currency Exposure Management at Transamerica", 1977 (Box 1)
  - The Economic Machine, An Introduction, 1978 Jul 24 (Box 1)
  - Transamerica Magazine, 1980 (Box 1)
  - A Long Term Fixed Rate Bond Issue, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Treasurers Department Review, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Matching Assets and Liabilities, some comments on theory (swaps), 1984 (Box 1)
  - Background Statement for 1985 Budget for Treasurer's Department, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Reducing Short Term Borrowing Costs by Using Swiss Francs, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Pound Exposure, 1986 (Box 1)
  - M. le Professeur Gerard Bramouille, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Increase in Future Income due to 1986 Debt and Interest Rate Swap Terminations, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Interest Rate Forecast, 1988 (Box 1)
  - "Measuring the Performance of Corporate Financial Officers", 1988 (Box 1)
  - Sterling Exposure re Sedgwick, 1989 (Box 1)
  - RE projections for value of yen, Swiss Franc and pound for three year period ending 1989, with attached memos from RE to the same group, and from John Beckett in 1982 on Inflation 1982-1994, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Outlook for U.K. Pound Sterling, 1990 (Box 1)
  - "Swaps at Transamerica: Analysis and Applications" (Box 1)
  - Focus on management issues of Hotel Group in light of worldwide recession, 1990 (Box 1)
- Academia
  - "Pierre-Joseph Proudhon," paper written as undergraduate fresh back from WWII (Timberwolf Division of Army, group trained at Princeton), 1948 (Box 1)
  - "General Equilibrium Analysis, " paper written for Professor Kenneth Boulding, University of Michigan, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Copy of Phi Cappa Phi Honor Society at University of Michigan, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Invitation to be considered as dean of Graduate School of Business Administration at Berkeley, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Complete Academic File, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Berkeley Program in Finance - Details re the program and Corporate Finance Seminar, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Berkeley Program in Finance Corporate Finance: Performance Measurement - Course Outline, 1988 (Box 1)
- Bohemian Club
  - Library Notes, 1985 Summer (Box 1)
  - Library Notes, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Birds of the Bohemian Grove, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Roster of Members, Officers Committees, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Book, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Library Notes, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Letter to Familiy re memorial book, 2007 (Box 1)
- Auerbach, Pollak & Richardson
  - "Everybody's Out of Step but Us: A Review of Developments Abroad", 1971 (Box 1)
  - "A Soft Dollar in a Hard World", 1972 (Box 1)
  - "Goodbye to Smithsonian", 1973 (Box 1)
- Robert Einzig and other publications
  - "The Flows of Funds Between Regions of the United States", 1958 Mar (Box 1)
  - Brochure about Investment Services (Box 1)
  - Berkeley Program in Finance: Corporate Finance, Performance Measurement, 1988 Mar 2 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - The California Savings and Loan Industry, 1963 (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Large Group Photo - Unidentified European Conference (Box 1)